{
  "id": "apes_ch14",
  "displayName": "Chapter 14",
  "questions": [
    {
      "number": 1,
      "question": "The science devoted to the study of the earth\u0027s surface and its interior is",
      "choices": ["geography.", "meteorology.", "cartography.", "geology."],
      "correct": 3
    },
    {
      "number": 2,
      "question": "Lithosphere is",
      "choices": [
        "the upper part of the mantel.",
        "composed of hard, solid (as opposed to softer, fluid) rock.",
        "the continental crust.",
        "all of the choices"
      ],
      "correct": 3
    },
    {
      "number": 3,
      "question": "Geologists call the liquid, molten rock nearest the earth\u0027s center the",
      "choices": ["crust.", "asthenosphere.", "outer core.", "lithosphere."],
      "correct": 2
    },
    {
      "number": 4,
      "question": "Regions of crust sometimes collide. These collision zones are called",
      "choices": [
        "transform faults.",
        "divergent plate boundaries.",
        "convergent plate boundaries.",
        "tectonic plates."
      ],
      "correct": 2
    },
    {
      "number": 5,
      "question": "A process that moves large pieces of rock would be",
      "choices": [
        "weathering.",
        "erosion.",
        "glaciation.",
        "all of the choices"
      ],
      "correct": 2
    },
    {
      "number": 6,
      "question": "Liquid rock flowing from active volcanoes is called",
      "choices": ["ash.", "lava.", "fissure.", "magma."],
      "correct": 1
    },
    {
      "number": 7,
      "question": "The worst volcanic disaster in U.S. history occurred at",
      "choices": [
        "Mount Washington in New Hampshire.",
        "Mount Hood in Oregon.",
        "Mount McKinley in Alaska.",
        "Mount St. Helens in Washington State."
      ],
      "correct": 3
    },
    {
      "number": 8,
      "question": "The specific point where an earthquake begins is called the",
      "choices": ["focus.", "amplitude.", "epicenter.", "seismic wave."],
      "correct": 0
    },
    {
      "number": 9,
      "question": "An earthquake reading of 6.8 on the Richter scale is ________ times more powerful than a reading of 5.8.",
      "choices": ["1.0", "100", "0.1", "10"],
      "correct": 3
    },
    {
      "number": 10,
      "question": "Earthquakes that occur on the ocean floor",
      "choices": [
        "all of the choices",
        "are called tsunamis.",
        "may cause tsunamis.",
        "are always deadly."
      ],
      "correct": 2
    },
    {
      "number": 11,
      "question": "Sodium chloride (table salt) in a water solution will dry to form crystals that we then identify",
      "choices": [
        "all of the choices",
        "sedimentary rock.",
        "rock.",
        "mineral."
      ],
      "correct": 0
    },
    {
      "number": 12,
      "question": "The interaction of physical and chemical processes that change rocks from one type to another is called the",
      "choices": [
        "hydrologic cycle.",
        "nitrogen cycle.",
        "rock cycle.",
        "carbon cycle."
      ],
      "correct": 2
    },
    {
      "number": 13,
      "question": "Limestone would best be classified as a",
      "choices": [
        "metallic mineral.",
        "renewable resource.",
        "fossil fuel.",
        "non-metallic mineral."
      ],
      "correct": 3
    },
    {
      "number": 14,
      "question": "A good, yet relatively inexpensive, low temperature conductor of electricity is",
      "choices": ["copper.", "molybdenum.", "platinum.", "carbon."],
      "correct": 0
    },
    {
      "number": 15,
      "question": "A major advantage of metallic minerals is that",
      "choices": [
        "they are recyclable.",
        "they cause little environmental degradation.",
        "they are always inexpensive to extract.",
        "the earth is constantly making more of them."
      ],
      "correct": 0
    },
    {
      "number": 16,
      "question": "Metal-mining waste material is called",
      "choices": ["gangue.", "ore.", "overburden.", "ore mineral."],
      "correct": 0
    },
    {
      "number": 17,
      "question": "Mineral resources",
      "choices": [
        "are non-renewable.",
        "are mostly concentrated in the U.S., Canada, Russia, South Africa, and Australia.",
        "all of the choices",
        "are distributed unevenly throughout the world."
      ],
      "correct": 2
    },
    {
      "number": 18,
      "question": "Given that metallic minerals are limited resources, depletion time",
      "choices": [
        "never factors in new discoveries of the mineral.",
        "is the time it takes to use up 80% of the reserves of a mineral at a given rate of use.",
        "all of the choices",
        "always factors in recycling and reuse."
      ],
      "correct": 1
    },
    {
      "number": 19,
      "question": "New technology(ies) that can be used to extract metals from low-grade ore include:",
      "choices": [
        "solar furnaces that create higher temperatures for smelting the ore.",
        "all of the choices",
        "new chemicals that remove metals from ores more efficiently.",
        "bacteria that can live in the ore, extracting/concentrating specific metals."
      ],
      "correct": 3
    },
    {
      "number": 21,
      "question": "Styrofoam has been found to be a suitable substitute for",
      "choices": [
        "concrete when sprayed with ceramic as a building material.",
        "steel and copper as pipe and conduit.",
        "electrical insulation around electric wires.",
        "steel and aluminum in auto bodies."
      ],
      "correct": 0
    }
  ]
}
